即将讲述的事件发生在1993年  1994年和1995年的10月3日
陪审团的女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
我并不是要站她们俩的某一边
I am not arguing one side of a "She said/she said" Matter.
我是来披露真相的
I'm here to expose the truth.
特纳小姐起诉沃利斯小姐诽谤
Ms. Turner is suing Ms. Wallis for defamation,
也就是说特纳小姐声称我的当事人
meaning Ms. Turner claims that my client
故意散播关于她的虚假信息
knowingly spread false information about her.
我们都恨同情沃利斯小姐...
While we all have deep sympathy for Ms. Wallis..
你怎么样
How are you holding up?
你很勇敢  凯特
You're brave, Kate!
这改变不了事实
...that doesn't change the fact
她犯法了
that she's broken the law.
没关系
It's okay.
证据的重压
The burden of proof
压在某个人的心头
rests on one person.
-珍妮特  -珍妮特  这边
- Jeanette! - Jeanette! Over here!
你后悔起诉凯特吗
Do you regret suing Kate?
你怎么安然自处的  珍妮特
How do you live with yourself, Jeanette?
那个人
And that person...
-1100万  认真的吗  -就是原告  特纳小姐
- 11 million? Seriously? - ...is the plaintiff, Ms. Turner.
-珍妮特  我们需要回答  -珍妮特  珍妮特
- Jeanette, we need some answers here. - Jeanette! Jeanette!
沃利斯小姐的谎言
Ms. Wallis's lie
将特纳小姐
transformed Ms. Turner
变成了全美公敌
into America's punching bag.
本案的重点并不是
This case isn't about the crimes
一起绑架案
of a disturbed kidnapper.
我的当事人已经承受了足够的痛苦
My client has already endured enough trauma.
这和沃利斯小姐被抓期间
And it has nothing to do
外界发生的一切
with what took place in the outside world
都没有关系
while Ms. Wallis was held captive.
这时的特纳小姐在享受我的当事人被抓所带来的好处
While Ms. Turner enjoyed the trappings of my client's life.
本案主要是为了玛莎贝利秀
This case is about Ms. Wallis's actions
人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
字幕组招新中
请访问 YYSubs.com
上面发生的一系列事
on The Marsha Bailey Show,
这严重损害了我的当事人
which have hurt my client's
翻译    小酸奶  Yang_Solitary
在未来的人生中
lifetime earning potential
估计约1100万的收入
to the tune of $11 million.
翻译    苏葵  Lark_Song
原告律师会试图攻击
The plaintiff's attorneys will attempt to attack
校对    小酸奶
我当事人的可信度
my client's integrity.
但证据只会显示
But the evidence will show
时间轴    爱撒谎的孩子  廉童伍
不可能
nothing.
证据会显示沃利斯小姐
The evidence will show that Ms. Wallis,
后期    吉吉
在全国性电视台上
on national television,
故意污蔑她
knowingly chose to defame her.
总监    小酸奶
没有证据显示
There is no evidence
我的当事人故意散播
that my client spread false information,
虚假信息
knowingly or otherwise.
我不嫉妒你
I don't envy you.
但我信任你
But I do trust you.
不是选择站边  而是选择真相
Not to choose sides but to choose the truth,
马上要揭露的真相
which is about to be revealed.
明天  我们将先开始原告陈述
Tomorrow we'll begin with the plaintiff's case in chief.
休庭
Court is adjourned.
残酷夏天
第一季第十集[季终]
我很高兴  你能同意这么做
I'm so happy you decided to do this.
你展现出了十足的魅力和可信度
Your look radiates integrity and elegance.
是你挑的
You picked it out.
玛莎贝利秀
沃利斯小姐  我们准备好了
Ms. Wallis, we're ready for you.
既然你上全国性电台之前不愿意戴耳环
Since you declined earrings and took a hatchet to your hair
还不愿意修头发
right before going on national TV...
很好
Yes.
她准备好了
She's ready.
你会做得很好的  亲爱的
You're gonna do great, honey.
有人找到了我
I was found by someone.
什么
Excuse me?
一个女孩
A girl.
我当时和她不熟
I didn't know her very well,
几乎不认识  但是
or at all, really, but...
那个保持沉默的女孩
to the girl who stayed silent,
你让我遭受了无法磨灭的痛苦
who let me endure things that I cannot erase...
珍妮特·特纳
Jeanette Turner...
我希望你烂在地狱里
I hope you rot in hell.
她不能这么做  她不能这样说出你的名字
She can't do that. She can't name you like that.
从法律上来说  她不能这么做
Legally, she can't do that.
你不该说出珍妮特的名字
You weren't supposed to mention Jeanette by name.
你就不该提
Or at all!
亲爱的  你违法了
Honey, you broke the law!
看来是轮到我了
My turn, I guess.
-凯特  这边  -凯特  凯特
- Kate, over here! - Kate, Kate!
拜托  莫莉  你知道我们不吃这套
Come on, Molly, you know better than that.
拜托
Oh, come on.
珍妮特  珍妮特
Jeanette, Jeanette!
你觉得1100万是狮子大开口吗
Would you agree that 11 million is a greedy number?
我们不会回答任何问题
We're not answering any questions right now.
你现在后悔你的举动吗
Do you regret any of your actions at all?
我们不会回答任何问题
We're not answering questions right now.
请后退
Back off, please.
我们走了  伙计们
We're done here, guys.
今天法庭上怎么样
How was court today?
今天还算轻松的
Today was easy.
明天  我的律师会召凯特
Tomorrow my lawyer's bringing Kate on the stand
做敌意证人
as a hostile witness.
这对你来说是好事
And that's good for you.
对吧
Right?
这也没法让人们喜欢我
Still won't make people like me.
我喜欢你
I like you.
特劳玛拉玛79  我为什么这么害怕明天的法庭
布伦奈斯4  因为那就是很可怕  但你可以的
特劳玛拉玛79  有什么建议吗  你以前上过法庭的
布伦奈斯4  小心选择你的措辞
特劳玛拉玛79  我就怕这个  我怕我说漏嘴
特劳玛拉玛79  我为什么这么害怕明天的法庭
布伦奈斯4  因为那就是很可怕  但你可以的
特劳玛拉玛79  有什么建议吗  你以前上过法庭的
布伦奈斯4  小心选择你的措辞
特劳玛拉玛79  我就怕这个  我怕我说漏嘴
布伦奈斯4  别担心  你可以的  辩论队队长
小家伙  你怎么还没睡
Doodlebug? What are you still doing up?
我没有直接从纸盒里挖冰淇淋
Not eating ice cream straight from the carton,
如果你想问的是这个的话
if that's what you're thinking.
我不是这个...
Well, I'm not thinking--
我想的是你应该给我也拿一个勺子
I'm thinking you should get me a spoon.
安吉拉说你很紧张
Angela says you're nervous.
你知道你还是有事可以和我说的  对吧
You know you can still talk to me, right?
嗯  爸爸
Yeah, Dad.
我知道
I do.
很好
Good.
沃利斯小姐  你曾多次声称
Ms. Wallis, you've stated repeatedly
马丁·哈里斯将你强制囚禁  对吗
that Martin Harris captured you by force, correct?
是的
Yes.
能请你再陈述一遍事情的经过吗
And what is it that you maintain happened?
马丁·哈里斯提出载我回家
Martin Harris offered me a ride home.
我上了车
I got in the car,
喝了他递给我的下药的汽水
drank the drugged soda he gave me,
就失去意识了  醒来发现在他家地下室
passed out, and woke up in his basement.
你对警察也是这样的说法  对吗
And that's what you relayed to the police, correct?
是的
It is.
你今天在这里也是同样的说法
And that's what you maintain here today,
在已经宣誓的情况下
under sworn oath.
是的
Yes.
法官大人  我有一份一页的文档
Your Honor, I have a one-page document
标明"四号证物"
marked "Exhibit 4."
可以递给证人吗
May I approach the witness?
反对  法官大人  未在证据发现阶段公布
Objection, Your Honor, this was not disclosed in discovery.
仅作质证之用  法官大人
It's for impeachment purposes, Your Honor.
保罗·加斯顿  法官
驳回  请继续
Overruled. You may continue.
沃利斯小姐  你手上拿的是什么
Ms. Wallis, what is it that you're holding?
一份打印的两个账号之间的聊天记录
A printed chat log between two screen names.
能请你念一下账户名吗
Could you please state those screen names?
布伦奈斯4和特劳玛拉玛79
Berenice4 and Traumarama79.
沃利斯小姐  能否请你念出高亮段落
Ms. Wallis, could you please read the highlighted passage?
沃利斯小姐
Ms. Wallis?
"特劳玛拉玛79"
"Traumarama79."
"我到马丁家里寻找安全感"
"I went to Martin's looking for safety."
"要是知道我是自愿前往  人们会怎么想"
"What would people think if they knew I went there willingly?"
"他们会怀疑整件事的真实性"
"It'd make them question my whole story."
你记得发生过这样的对话吗  沃利斯小姐
Do you recall this conversation, Ms. Wallis?
是不是应该叫你特劳玛拉玛79
Or should I call you Traumarama79?
这是你的网名  对吗
That is your screen name, correct?
我不明白
I don't understand.
那些聊天内容是隐私
Those chats were private.
他们监听了我们的电话吗  这合法吗
Did they tap our phones? Can they do that?
我查了查
I did some digging.
看来你姐姐一直以网名"布伦奈斯4"的名义
It appears that your sister has been chatting
和你聊天
under the screen name "Berenice4."
你父母在给她打电话
Your parents are calling her now.
布伦奈斯就是艾希莉
Berenice is Ashley?
凯特
Kate.
你没有对我说实话
You haven't been honest with me.
问题很大
And that's a problem.
这对我们的案子是很大的打击
This is a huge blow to our case.
如果你还有什么瞒着我的
If there is anything else you're not telling me...
马上告诉我
I need to know.
你来这里干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
我的所作所为无法用语言弥补
There's no apologizing for what I did.
我不该喝酒
I shouldn't have been drinking.
不该开车载你  却偏偏载了
I shouldn't have given you a ride, but I did.
我没有理由
There's no excuse.
我对发生的一切负全部责任
I take full responsibility for what happened.
真不错  杰米  你可以走了
Well, that's great, Jamie. You can go now.
但文斯·富勒什么也没做错
But Vince Fuller didn't do anything wrong.
布伦奈斯4  "凯特  抱歉让你以这样的方式发现真相"
布伦奈斯4"我想让你有人可以谈谈心"
布伦奈斯4"但现实中你从来不和我说话"
布伦奈斯4"给我打电话  拜托了"
特劳玛拉玛79  "你怎么能这么对我"
老天爷
Holy shit.
艾希莉就是布伦奈斯
Ashley is Berenice?
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我真的败了  玛洛丽
I'm bugging out, Mal.
她说原因了吗
Did she say why?
说了  还用这种完全站不住脚的借口
Yeah, and she had this weak-ass excuse
说我需要有人谈心
of, "I needed someone to talk to."
这倒挺贴心的
That sounds... nice.
我以为我找到了同类
I thought I had found someone like me.
经历了地狱般的生活存活下来的人
Who had been through hell and back and survived it.
我以为在和未来的我聊天
I thought that I was chatting with my future,
结果她根本不存在
and she doesn't even exist.
事情的全貌还是拼不完整
I don't have the whole puzzle.
我没料到布伦奈斯的身份
I was wrong about Berenice
也记不起安娜贝尔是谁
and I don't remember Anabelle.
要是我知道的根本不是全貌呢
What if I don't have all the pieces?
我想是时候
I think I'm ready
试试西尔维亚的办法了
to try what Sylvia suggested.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我们还没有开门  请稍后
We're actually not open yet if you wanna...
真的很对不起
I'm so sorry.
为什么现在说这个
Why are you saying this now?
杰米让我想了很多
Jamie got me thinking.
我一直在惩罚错的人
About how... I've been punishing the wrong person.
而且我很想你
And I miss you.
过了这么久
It's been so long.
我听到也没有多开心
I can't even enjoy hearing that.
我做错什么了
What did I do that was so wrong?
在我男朋友受伤的时候陪在他身边
Be there for my boyfriend when he got hurt?
是我太敏感了
I was vulnerable.
大家都在看着我
I mean, everyone was staring and...
这时候你决定替我们两个出柜
and that's when you tried to out us.
那一刻除了我们两个
I wasn't thinking about anyone else in that moment
我没有心思去想别人
except for you and me.
我害怕极了  文斯
I was terrified, Vince.
你以为我不怕吗
You think I'm not scared?
我是黑人  还是同性恋
I'm black. And gay.
身处德克萨斯
In Texas.
我们是一起面对这一切的  本
We were in this together, Ben.
结果你把我弃如敝履
You just tossed me anywhere.
你说得对
You're right.
你不用现在就答复我
You don't have to answer me right now.
但我想重新赢得你的信任
But I want to earn your trust back.
如果你愿意的话
If you'll let me.
你真的想在这里见面
You really wanted to meet me here?
明明有那么多地方可以去
Of all places?
这里是真相埋藏的地方
This is where the truth lies.
我们两个都想要真相  对吗  珍妮特
And that's what we both want, right, Jeanette?
从去年夏天起我就想和你一起面对真相
I've wanted to face the truth with you since last summer.
怎么现在想起来了
Why now?
从我家手里赢走1100万伤害不到我
Taking $11 million from my family won't hurt me.
但会让我父母一贫如洗
But it will completely bankrupt my parents.
所以你看我要赢了
So now that you think I might win,
突然愿意庭外和解了
you're interested in settling this outside of court?
伤天害理的事你没少干  珍妮特
You've done some dirty shit, Jeanette,
但把聊天记录当庭甩在我脸上太没品了
but springing those chat logs on me in court was a low blow.
在电视上公开我的名字才低劣
Naming me on TV was a low blow.
你偷走了我的创伤日记
You stole what was basically my trauma journal
并在法庭上公开
and shared it in a courtroom.
你看不出来这有多残忍吗
Can you not see how cruel that is?
你看不出自己毁了我的生活吗
Can you not see that you ruined my life?
-你偷走了我的  -反正你也不想要
- You stole mine! - You didn't even want it!
我看了好多好多页
I have read pages and pages
你和布伦奈斯的对话
of your chat with Berenice.
我并不知道整个故事
And I don't know the whole story.
但我知道你很幸运
But I know that you're lucky
马丁·哈里斯确实有不可告人的秘密
that there are some serious secrets buried with Martin Harris.
我是莫莉·格林  站在斯凯林法院的前方
I'm Molly Green, standing on the steps of Skylin Courthouse,
珍妮特·特纳和凯特·沃利斯
where Jeanette Turner and Kate Wallis
在特纳诉沃利斯一案的第三天
have both yet to appear on day three
均尚未出现
of Turner v. Wallis.
事件的更多真相正浮出水面
More on this story as it unfolds.
既然你说我偷了你的生活
Since you're accusing me of stealing your life,
那杰米呢
what about Jamie?
你在失踪前就跟他分手了
You were over him before you went missing.
但当你回来后
But when you came back,
却依然夺走了他  即使你知道我爱他
you reclaimed him anyway, even though I loved him.
对  那是因为你不遗余力地把我留在地狱
Yeah, you went to great sick lengths to leave me in hell
好让自己拥有他
in order to keep him.
-我没有  -那我们直说吧
- I didn't. - Let's get to it, then.
什么
What?
我没什么可隐瞒的
I don't have anything to hide.
我知道你闯入过这栋房子
I know you broke into this house.
对  为了玩捉迷藏
Yeah. To play hide-and-seek.
这不是秘密  我去年就告诉警察了
That's no secret. I told the cops that last year.
不  不是那次
No, not that time.
我知道你在93年平安夜又进来过一次
I know you did it again on Christmas Eve in '93.
好吧
Okay.
但我那天没有去地下室
But I didn't go into the basement that day.
所以如果你知道  那我猜你也没有在地下室
So if you know that, then I guess you weren't in the basement, either?
你说得对  我不在
You're right, I wasn't.
看来我们还真是坦诚相待了
So we're really being honest.
反正我是  我知道你看到了我
I am. I know you saw me.
我知道我没看到你
And I know I didn't.
上船
All aboard!
你闯入的那夜  我一个人在家
The night you broke in, I was home alone.
你觉得我会任由你这个红发小鬼
You think I'd let a funny little redhead like you
到处乱跑吗
run around loose here?
茱莉  我必须要拥有你
Julia, I've got to have you!
-我在玩...  -雪球
- And I was messing with... - The snow globe.
你怎么知道
How could you know that?
你还在打电话  对吧
You were making a phone call, right?
杰米在答录机上收到了一通奇怪的留言
Jamie got this weird message on his answering machine.
我们觉得可能是你
We thought it might be you,
但根本说不通
but, I mean, it didn't make any sense.
你被绑架了怎么还能打电话呢
How could you have been making a phone call while you were kidnapped?
这是杰米的私人电话
You've reached Jamie's private line.
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
留言莫名其妙  只有呼吸声
The message was nonsense. It was breathing...
当我听到那个跑调的雪球后
Once I heard that out-of-tune snow globe,
我知道是你从楼上打的电话
I knew you called from upstairs.
直到死亡把我们分离
Till death do us part.
你看见我的那晚  我藏在二楼
The night you saw me, I hid on the second floor.
有人吗
Hello?
我确定没人在家
I was sure no one was home.
我在商场看到了马丁·哈里斯
I saw Martin Harris at the mall.
然后我听到了一个声音
And then I heard a noise.
我拿上雪球后就走了
I took the snow globe and I left.
我找到了你的项链
I found your necklace.
加油姐妹
如果项链能证明什么  我早就被捕了
If the necklace proved anything, I'd be arrested by now.
我难道不知道吗
Don't I know it.
我往窗外一看  看到了你的自行车
I looked out this window and I saw your bike.
但你没看到我的脸  对吧
But you didn't see my face, did you?
我听到了你的声音  我找到了你的项链
I heard your voice, I found your necklace.
我看到你的自行车
And I saw your bike.
你撒谎
You lied.
是没跟你对视吗
About holding eye contact, I guess?
你的脸在外被阴影遮住
Your face was shadowed outside,
但你朝着我  我看到了你的自行车
but you were facing me and I saw your bike
轮子上还有愚蠢的卡片
with the stupid card on the wheel.
天呐
Oh, my God.
那是我的自行车
Hey, that's my bike!
-谁在乎  -快走
- Who cares? - Go, go, go!
有手提音响的自行车吗
The bike with the boombox?
快啊  我们得走了
Come on, we have to go!
还有卡片吗
And the card?
那不是我的自行车
That's not my bike.
是玛洛丽的
It's Mallory's.
什么
What?
是玛洛丽看见了你
Mallory's the one who saw you.
玛洛丽吗
It was Mallory?
那怎么可能
How is that even possible?
妈的  你这回肯定要被抓了
Oh, shit. You are so getting busted.
玛洛丽之后告诉我说她看见我闯进去
Mallory told me later she saw me broke in.
她希望我能被抓
She was hoping to see me get caught.
她肯定等到了我离开
She must have waited until I left.
然后她决定跟踪我
And then she decided to follow me.
那时你看到了玛洛丽  以为是我
That must be when you saw Mallory and you thought it was me.
你这次又偷了什么
What did you steal this time?
-什么  -你因为清单的事对我说教
- What? - You lectured me about the list,
还有违禁品
about the contraband.
你表现得比我道德高尚
You played holier-than-thou
直到你不再跟我做朋友
right up until cutting me off as a friend,
而你一直以来都在偷偷溜进那房子里吗
when you've been sneaking into that house this entire time?
-我...  -你那么做肯定感觉很爽  对吧
- I, um... - You get some sort of sick pleasure out of it, don't you?
真不敢相信你还没被捕
I can't believe you haven't gotten caught yet.
你这个伪君子  而且说真的还是个怪胎
You're a hypocrite and honestly a real weirdo.
我不是怪胎
I'm not a weirdo.
听着  如果你这么在乎  拿走吧
Look, if you care so much, just take it.
我们都不是朋友了  你为什么在乎我干什么
We're not even friends anymore, why do you care what I do?
拿走这愚蠢的东西  赶紧走
So just take the stupid thing and get out.
赶紧走
Go!
我把雪球给了玛洛丽
I gave Mallory the snow globe.
她不肯还给我
She wouldn't give it back.
可能是为保护你
Probably to protect you.
搜搜她的房间  你肯定能找到雪景球
If you search her room, I'm sure you'll find it.
你没撒谎
You're not lying.
真的是玛洛丽看到了我
It was really Mallory that saw me.
我没看到你
I didn't see you.
当时  如果知道我搞错了
If I didn't think I was right,
我根本不会指控你
I would have never accused you.
珍妮特  我太对不起你了
Jeanette, I am so sorry.
我能问一下
Can I ask...
你俩在这屋里都发生什么了吗
what happened between you two in this house?
我和马丁
We were friends.
曾是朋友
Martin and I.
曾经
He was...
他友善  富有魅力
kind and fascinating.
我真的不知如何形容
I don't really know how else to describe it.
-他似乎  -像是有很多秘密的人吗
- He seemed... - Like someone who had secrets?
对
Yeah.
我在这过了一夜
I slept over that first night.
那晚过后  我就住下了
That night led to more nights.
和他也不仅是友情了
And friends led to more than friends.
你们曾经
You two were...
后来事情变得很黑暗
Things escalated to a really dark place.
只是有件事  我想不起来
There's just one thing that I can't remember.
心理医生告诉我
And my therapist says that...
要是我回到那下面
if I go back down there,
可能有助于我想起来
that maybe it will help unlock the memory.
回到地下室吗
Down to the basement?
你要和我一起吗
Will you come with me?
好
Yes.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我获救的那晚  他到地下室来了
The night before I was rescued, he came down here.
和之前不同
Something was different.
有些不对劲
Something was wrong.
他很憔悴
He was vulnerable
但似乎又平静得不对劲
but weirdly seemed at peace.
看起来他好像
Seemed like he had...
做出了什么决定
made a decision.
当时以为  他鼓足勇气要杀我
Thought he had worked up the courage to actually kill me.
曾经你问一切将如何结束
You asked me once how this ends.
我试过想其他办法
I've tried to find another way,
但没有办法
but there isn't one.
马丁
Martin...
我们会想到的
we can find one.
不
No.
今天警察来了
The police came here today.
是吗
They did?
他们拿着搜查令回来这儿取证
It's only a matter of time
只是时间问题
before they're back with a search warrant.
这是安娜贝尔
This is Anabelle.
是传家宝
She's a family heirloom.
你为什么要把她带下来
Why did you bring her down here?
她夺走了我父亲的生命
She took my father's life.
你要用她取我性命吗
Are you gonna take mine?
我为我做过的事
I'm sorry for the things I've done.
以及接下来要做的事  感到抱歉
For what I'm about to do.
求求你  马丁  不要
Martin, please, no.
这是唯一的办法
It's the only way.
去过你的生活吧
Go live your life.
去看我们曾经畅想的世界
See the world like we wanted.
记得我曾深深爱过你
And know that you were truly loved.
永别了  凯特
Goodbye, Kate.
凯特
Kate?
听我说  好吗
Listen to me, okay?
我做错了
I was wrong.
这是你我之间的事
It's me and you.
我们会找到办法的
We'll find a way.
把枪给我  好吗
Just give me the gun, okay?
你不会想要这么做的
You don't wanna do this.
你爱我
You love me.
整夜  我都守着他
I sat with him all night.
我内心乱作一团
I felt paralyzed.
对他的爱
And guilty for loving him.
他的恨
And for hating him.
还为杀死他而悔恨不已
And killing him.
到了早上  我报了警
In the morning, I called the cops.
可新闻报道他和警方交火而身亡
The news said he died in a shootout.
可能因为他死于枪伤
They assumed that, I guess,
才有这样的猜测报道
because he died of a gunshot wound.
什么声音
What was that?
不久后  我可能也用外界的说法
I think I might have internalized that, too,
说服了自己
after a while.
我的心理医生说  这事有可能发生
My therapist says that can happen.
我才是那个坏人
I'm the bad guy.
不
No.
拜托  没人会责怪你杀了马丁
Come on, no one could blame you for killing him.
珍妮特  你应该告我
Jeanette, you should sue me.
你不该遭受这些
You didn't deserve any of this.
你去吧  拿走赔偿金
You should go, take the money.
压根就不是赔偿金的问题
It was never about the money.
那是什么
Then what was it about?
自始至终
All I ever wanted...
我可能
was to just...
只是想体验下你过的生活
maybe feel what it was like
是什么感受
to be like you.
不是说我要变成你  就是
Not to actually be you, just...
我从没感到过
I never felt like I was...
受人欢迎  或是
popular or...
美丽动人
beautiful,
心满意足
or enough.
我只是想知道那都是什么感觉
I just wanted to know what that felt like.
一次就好
To just once...
沐浴在阳光下的感觉
have the sun shining on me.
是的  我被绑架过
Yes, I was kidnapped.
这就是真相
That's the truth.
和珍妮特·特纳深入交谈后
After speaking to her in depth myself,
还有一事  我万分确定
there is another truth that I am 100% certain of.
珍妮特·特纳没在马丁·哈里斯家中看见我
Jeanette Turner did not see me in Martin Harris's house.
她不是媒体所报道的恶人
She is not the monster the media has made her out to be.
珍妮特·特纳是一名受害者
Jeanette Turner is a victim.
凯特  所以说你撒谎了吗
Kate, does that make you a liar?
污蔑一名无辜女孩  你作何感想呢
How do you feel dragging an innocent girl's name through the mud?
凯特  是什么促使你这样做呢
What prompted this, Kate?
是要去哪儿吗
Going somewhere?
玛洛丽  我知道你看到了我
Mal, I know you saw me.
你和我做朋友
You befriended me.
却对你看见我这事  只字不提
And didn't say a word to me about it.
对
Yes.
这两件事怎么能共存呢
How are both of those things true?
你欠我个解释
I deserve an explanation.
我不知道
I don't know.
拜托  玛洛丽  对我掩饰什么
Come on, Mal, it's me.
我看到一名女子行动自由
I saw a woman living freely...
没被关在地下室
not in the basement.
我以为是马丁·哈里斯的女友
I figured it was Martin Harris's girlfriend
或者是姐妹  或是
or... sister or...
别的什么人
something.
你说对了一半
You were half-right.
一名失踪的女孩在别人家客厅打电话
It-it didn't make sense for a missing girl
我当时觉得这说不通
to be in the living room making a call.
你就是那时候看见我的
That's when you saw me.
我压根想不到  那会是你
I never in a million years imagined that it was you.
为什么
Why would you?
从新闻上得知你获救前
I didn't really think much of it
我根本没多想过
until I heard about your rescue on the news.
绑匪在激烈的交火中  中枪身亡
And her abductor has been killed in a deadly shootout.
我们的新闻小组就在现场
Our news team was there on the scene.
事件出现了惊人  可怕的转折
And in a shocking and disturbing turn of events,
少女凯特·沃利斯获救
凯特·沃利斯指控马丁·哈里斯为绑架者
Kate Wallis's alleged kidnappr was Martin Harris,
马丁·哈里斯曾是斯凯林高中助理校长
who was the assistant principl at Skylin High School in Texa.
而且所有人都认为你被关在地下室
And the world only thought you were ever in the basement.
我说出秘密就等于拆穿了你
Telling my secret meant telling yours, too.
所以我思前想后  觉得这与我无关
So I chalked it up to being none of my business.
然后
And...
然后我们成了朋友
then we became friends.
还有  我
And I...
你真没劲啊
Boo, you're no fun!
我
I...
不是说要坦诚相待吗
What happened to "No more secrets"?
我这就坐长途汽车  离开镇子
I'm gonna hop a Greyhound and get out of town.
再也不会出现在你面前
You will never see me again.
把我丢在这儿
And leave me?
离开吗
Here?
离我而去吗
Without you?
我不准
Don't you dare.
片场保持安静
Quiet on set.
一个月后
好了  开机
Okay, go!
等下  好了
Hold. Okay.
坐在我身边的是珍妮特·特纳
I'm sitting here with Jeanette Turner,
这位姑娘曾被深深地误解
the young woman at the center of a misunderstanding
一年来  她的生活和内心都备受影响
that cost a year of her life and her sanity.
此时此刻
She is, in this moment,
她就是全美最冤屈的女性
the most wronged woman in America.
珍妮特
Jeanette...
你坚韧不拔  通情达理
given your resilience, your grace,
顽强不屈
your strength...
你的事迹鼓舞人心
you are an inspiration.
对你造成的误解  也有我的过失
And for the part I played in what happened to you,
我深感抱歉
I am deeply sorry.
谢谢你  玛莎
Thank you, Marsha.
今日在此受访  我倍感荣幸
I'm incredibly grateful to be here today.
我曾观看
I've watched and...
我知道你现在满心都是和谐与宽容
I know you're all kumbaya and forgiveness now,
但是
but...
我现在就是在看一个彻头彻尾的怪胎秀
what I'm watching is an absolute creep show.
可能吧
Maybe.
但不巧这是个无辜的怪胎
But that creep also happens to be innocent.
我们开车兜风去吧
Let's go for a drive.
要说我从这一切中学到了什么
...if there's one thing I've learned from all this...
-我们去哪  -我不得不问
- Where are we going? - I have to ask...
你终止了对凯特的诉讼
You dropped the lawsuit against Kate,
放弃了近在咫尺的1100万调解金
walking away from a potential $11 million settlement.
你为何这么做
What made you do that?
玛莎  这压根就不是钱的问题
It was never about the money, Marsha.
唯有真相才重要
Only the truth.
现在真相大白了
And now that the truth has come out,
如今  你的生活过得怎样呢
what does life look like on the other side?
我有最好的爸爸  他一直支持我
Well, I have the greatest dad who never left my side,
还有我梦寐以求的完美男友
and... the best boyfriend I could hope for.
访谈结束前  你还有什么
Is there anything else you'd like to share
想说的吗
before you wrap up?
那个曾经在此对我指名道姓的女生
There is something I want to say.
我有话想对你说
To the girl who named me.
你本可以早日澄清事件  但你没那么做
Who could have cleared all this up sooner but didn't.
凯特·沃利斯
Kate Wallis...
我原谅你
I forgive you.
该死
shit!
我爱这首歌
I love this song!
这次你得和我下车一起跳舞
You are getting out and dancing with me this time.
好呀  好
Okay, fine.
来吧
Come on!
有人吗
Hello?
是马丁吗
Martin?
有人吗
Is someone there?
能听到我的话  我是凯特·沃利斯
If anyone can hear me, it's Kate Wallis!
能听到吗
Can you hear me?
马丁把我关在下面了  请救救我
Martin's locked me down here. Please help me!
请救我出去吧
Please help me out!
有人吗
Is anybody there?